NALIN LUTHRA

9999795087 nalin.luthra@gmail.com

2019

2018

2017

Profile

A curious, polyglot and polymath who like to learn and solve problem irrespective of field. Notable contribution in research field with mostly novel ideas, that are usually out of box. Learning about new technologies, brain storming on ideas and reading books is everyday job & hobby.

Internship and Industry Experience

Matrix Geo (Intern)	2020
Research and development on LiDAR and IMU for 3D Mapping	
OYO Full Stack Web Developer (Freelancing)	2019

OYO Full Stack Web Developer (Freelancing)Development of SAAS using MEAN Stack for sales team, to make sales easy by providing search and

dynamic calculation of different itinerary.

IntellitTicks Full Stack Web Developer (Intern) My day to day task consists of product development and feature addition. Fixing bugs and managing code

My day to day task consists of product development and feature addition. Fixing bugs and managing code base of existing features.

Centre of Artificial Intelligence and Robotics (Project Intern)

Our task was to develop automated path and its navigation without human pilot drone navigation system.

FabHotels (Intern) 2017

Video Editing and Advertisement designing

Tirupati Medicos (Freelancing)Designed a inventory management and POS system on java and SQL. So multiple shops can share same

Designed a inventory management and POS system on java and SQL. So multiple shops can share same inventory and information about medicines.

Achievements and Award

Research Publications

•	Hack BMU First Position	2019	Vanita Jain, Gopal Chaudhary, Nalin Luthra , Akshit Rao, Shlok Walia "Dynamic Handwritten Signature and Machine Learning Based Identification verification for keyless Cryptocurrency
•	Brainwaves Societe Generale 6th Position	2019	Transactions", ICDSSA 2019 Special Issue: Journal of Information and Optimization Sciences (JIOS), Taylor and Francis
•	Smart India Hackathon, Grand Final Finalist (Bhopal)	2018	Tallois
•	Technoxian - WRC (World Robotic Championship), 3rd Position across 300 teams and 20 Countries , Sponsored by Govt. of India, Ministry of Science	2017	Vanita Jain, Gopal Chaudhary, Nalin Luthra , Akshit Rao, Harman Singh "How to help Johnny travel in Brimming train?" ICDSSA 2019, Lecture Notes in Electrical Engineering (Springer book series)
•	and Technology, RoboRace	2017	Nalin Luthra , Vanita jain, Gopal Chaudhary "Temperature invariant and high precision absolute rotary encoder using photocells on visible light spectrum" (Under Review)
•	Delhi Times Fresh Face college Winner.	2016	Nalin Luthra, Vanita Jain "Medical Assistance using drone for remote areas"

Technical Skills

- Languages/Databases :- C/C++, Python, Java, Processing, MATLAB, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB and URDF
- Frameworks/Tools :- NodeJs, ROS (Robotics Operating System), Angular, RVIZ, Meteor, OpenCV, Gazebo and Unreal Engine
- Hardware :- Ardunio, Raspberry pi, ESP8266 and 8085 Microprocessor
- Technologies :- Computer Vision, IOT, Machine Learning, Drones, Robotics, Web Technologies and Cyber Security.

Education

The Air Force School Class 10th	9.0 CGPA	2014
The Air Force School Class 12th	PCMB with Computer Science 94.5%	2016
College - BVCOE (IPU)	Π	2016-Present

Positions and Leadership Experience

Chairperson (Indian Society of Technical Education)	2019-Present
Head of Technical Affairs (Indian Society of technical education BVP)	2018-2019
Taken a session on Robotics at DTU under ROSPi-Jam	2018
Head of Robotic Society Electronika (BVP-ISTE)	2017-2018
Leading team of 25 Students to Build Home Automation and Self Driving car	2017-2018
Publicity Head (ACM-BVP)	2017-2018
Teaching Robotics to Students (1st - 4th Year)	2017-2018
Teaching Programming to Students (1st - Year)	2017-2018
Event manager (BVP-ISTE)	2016-2017
Graphic Designer Executive (ACM-BVP)	2016-2017
Event manager Executive (TEDxBVP)	2016-2017
Head Co-curricular The Air Force School	2014-2016

Miscellaneous

Google Local guide : Level 7 Contributor

Technical Projects

•	Portable PHP server on Raspberry Pi	2020
•	Non Invasive electricity monitoring system with prediction for budget planning	2019-2020
•	PacBot (Indoor Navigation and Visualising physical world using ROS)	2018
•	Indoor navigation	2018
•	Self Driving Car using computer vision and ultrasonic sensors	2017-Present
•	Home Automation using Raspberry pi and IOT sensors with firebase and NodeJs	2017-2018
•	Eye - Blinking Detection for Security and Surveillance	2017-2018
•	Farming Drone to prevent snakes and other animals enter in the farm land	2018
•	Raspberry Pi - 3 based personal Cloud Storage	2018
•	CNC - Machine using waste	2017
•	Air-Piano	2017
•	Drone (Using KK2 flight Controller)	2017
•	Laptop Controlled Car using ZigBee Communication and self made software using	2017
	Processing (JAVA). Working radius 1.2 Km.	
•	Self Balancing Bot	2017
•	Line Following Robot (Using PID and LDR)	2017

Hobbies

• Chess • ICE Skating • Rapping (Hip-Hop)

Reading booksPhotographyRunning

Novels
 Motivational Speaker
 Online gaming

• Swimming • Painting

References

- 1. **Prof. Dr. Vanita Jain, (Dean of Academics)** Vice-Principal, Bharati Vidhyapeeth College of Engineering, New Delhi
- 2. Deepika Thapar Singh, CEO-Principal Credence High School Dubai (Ex-Principal The Air Force School)